We saw previously that
our project Vagrantfile
can override settings found
in the box Vagrantfile.
We overrode the default rsync synced
folder and made a VirtualBox synced folder,
configured with the same paths,
in its place.
This was possible because settings
configured in the project Vagrantfile
have higher precedence
than those in the box Vagrantfile.
Last time, we introduced
a third Vagrantfile:
the one found
in your vagrant home directory.
I mentioned that settings in this file
apply to all the projects of a user.
The topic of Vagrantfile precedence
is increasing in complexity as we go.
Thankfully, the Vagrantfile page
found in the vagrant documentation
includes a comprehensive overview
of this topic.
We can see here that
the box Vagrantfile is loaded first
and, therefore,
has the lowest precedence.
The vagrant home Vagrantfile is next,
followed by the project Vagrantfile.
There are additional precedence concerns
in multimachine environments
or when overriding non-provider specific
configuration from within a provider block--
these are out-of-scope
for now.
Last time, we used our
vagrant home Vagrantfile
to skip guest additions
installation by default.
Let's restore our VirtualBox synced folder
using only our project Vagrantfile.
We'll uncomment the kernel upgrade
and VirtualBox synced folder lines.
Then set `vbguest.auto_update`
to `true`.
Based on what we read
in the documentation about precedence,
the `vbguest.auto_update = true`
in our project Vagrantfile
should override the `false` value
in our vagrant home Vagrantfile.
Let's bring up
our machine.
And login.
We can see the VirtualBox kmods are loaded
and the /vagrant directory
is of type `vboxsf`--
this is indeed a VirtualBox synced folder.
Time to clean up.
Feel free to revert
the changes made last time
to your vagrant home Vagrantfile now--
if you so choose.
Doing so will restore
the vagrant-vbguest default
of automatic installation
of guest additions.