Another interesting GUI tool,
especially when using vagrant frequently,
is Vagrant Manager.
Per the project README, "Vagrant Manager
is a Windows status bar menu app that lets
you manage all of your vagrant machines
from one central location."
Vagrant Manager is also
available for macOS.
However, unfortunately, Vagrant Manager
isn't available on Linux distros,
like Ubuntu,
at present.
We're back on our Windows 10
baremetal environment
with the PSWindowsUpdate PowerShell module,
VirtualBox, and vagrant installed.
Vagrant Manager requires the `vagrant`
command to be in your `$env:PATH`--
we just verified that this need is met
with our version check.
Next, we want to ensure
that our environment is up-to-date.
The basic environment is.
If updates are needed, they can
be installed with a few extra flags.
Be sure to only use the `-AutoReboot` flag
if now is a suitable time for a reboot.
With our system updated,
we're ready to install Vagrant Manager.
Let's download the Vagrant Manager
setup executable from the latest release.
Unfortunately, this project doesn't provide
us with the means to validate our download--
no checksums or similar
are included.
However, hope is not lost.
Chocolatey is a well-known
package manager
facilitating automated software
installations on Windows.
This package manager itself
is out-of-scope for now,
but that doesn't mean we can harvest
some useful information from the project.
The Chocolatey install PowerShell script
for Vagrant Manager
includes a SHA-256 of the same setup `.exe`
we just downloaded.
Verifying that our download
has the same SHA-256
reduces our chances of unnoticed
file corruption or tampering.
For basic validation of an asset securely
downloaded from a trusted domain--
such as this--I'm comfortable
with a simple visual comparison.
I generally compare
the first and last 4-6 characters,
then check one or two random spots
in the middle.
Compare the hashes programmatically
as you see fit.
This download looks good to me.
Research Vagrant Manager and Chocolatey
as needed and move forward if you so choose.
The Chocolatey PowerShell script
also gives us
the arguments needed
to have a silent, promptless install.
Let's install Vagrant Manager by running
the setup `.exe` with these arguments.
This will both install
and open Vagrant Manager--
which can take
several seconds.
To access Vagrant Manager
once it's running,
click the newly introduced
"V" icon
in the notification area
at the right end of the Windows taskbar.
Our install looks good.
To finalize initial setup,
there's one more step--
and we're only prompted the second time
we open Vagrant Manager on Windows.
Let's exit and wait
for the "V" icon to disappear.
Then reopen Vagrant Manager--
I'm going to do so via PowerShell,
but using the Start menu
will work just as well.
On second open,
we're immediately met
with a Vagrant Manager prompt
about automatic updates.
I'm going to decline for now,
but feel free to accept as you see fit.
And we're done.