Here we have our new install
of Vagrant Manager:
a GUI tool providing centralized management
of vagrant machines.
Vagrant Manager is only available
on macOS and Windows at present.
So, we're back on our
macOS 12.6.3 baremetal environment.
I've copied our demo project
over from my Ubuntu environment.
And I've installed vagrant-vbguest
in my macOS environment.
Finally, I created and destroyed this
vagrant managed machine a few minutes ago.
This ensures that the one time
events and operations we've already seen,
like box download,
have been triggered.
At this point, my macOS vagrant setup
should be in the same essential state
as my Ubuntu vagrant setup was
when we last saw it.
Let's open Vagrant Manager.
Currently, it doesn't
show any machines.
Let's refresh--
still nothing.
This is an important take away:
without additional configuration,
Vagrant Manager ignores machines
in the "not created" state.
Let's bring up
our machine.
Time to refresh again.
Now we can see a menu entry
for our project in Vagrant Manager.
Hover over the entry
and a menu of options will be presented.
With a single click on "SSH",
Vagrant Manager will open a terminal,
change to the project directory,
and run `vagrant ssh`.
One click and we're
logged in to our vm.
By selecting "Open in Terminal",
Vagrant Manager will open a terminal
and change to the project directory--
no automated `vagrant ssh` this time.
However, you'll land
in the project directory
with the full command line,
including `vagrant ssh`, at your disposal.
Let's select "SSH"
to login to our machine.
Now we have a new terminal window sitting
at the prompt of our internal environment.
We can run any commands available
in our vm like normal.
When ready,
we can log out.
And we end up at the prompt
of our external environment.
This is the same place where "Open
in Terminal" would have taken us directly.
Here we can run any commands available
to our baremetal environment like normal.
Surprise, surprise,
our machine is running.
Close out of the terminal window
using standard methods when ready.
As we saw a moment ago,
Vagrant Manager won't present machines
in the "not created" state.
If we destroy this machine,
it will be removed from the menu.
If you want specific machines present
in Vagrant Manager even when "not created",
you can bookmark them.
Let's do so
for demo now.
And then destroy
from Vagrant Manager.
Click confirm to move forward
with the destruction.
A task window opens
and runs `vagrant destroy` on our behalf.
Let's close
out of that.
We can see that Vagrant Manager
has an entry for demo
despite the fact that
it's in the "not created" state.
Now we can bring up our machine
using Vagrant Manager.
A task window opens
and runs `vagrant up` for us.
Vagrant Manager exposes many
useful vagrant actions in clickable form.
If you're most comfortable
using a GUI environment,
this tool may become a significant part
of your vagrant workflow.
My main use case for Vagrant Manager
is to quickly locate abandoned vms.
When priorities shift suddenly,
it's all too easy to leave machines behind,
needlessly consuming
finite resources.
For me, Vagrant Manager simplifies
reclaiming cpu, memory,
and storage resources currently tied up
by discarded vagrant machines.
Let's clean up.