We previously learned that
`vagrant halt` can be used
to persist the internal storage
of vagrant managed machines.
However, often you will want to reclaim
these storage resources
when stepping away
from a project.
We also learned that `vagrant up` provides
us with a solid starting environment.
Generally, the next step
is customizing that environment
by deploying code
and config.
Frequently, this step includes
files sourced from our project root.
vagrant just wouldn't
be complete without
a way to copy files
into and out of machines.
Thankfully, it provides
a mechanism for this: synced folders.
There are several types
of synced folders supported by vagrant.
Let's begin with the default
synced folder type
shipped with our
`centos/7` box, rsync.
Let's create a file
in our project root.
And bring our
machine up.
We can see the file exists
inside our vm too, in /vagrant.
Let's log out and modify the file
by adding some contents.
The modification isn't present
inside the vm.
In the case
of rsync synced folders,
we need to run `vagrant rsync`
to transfer the change in.
And now we
can see our modification.
Next, let's create a file,
inside the vm,
in the /vagrant directory.
This file isn't present
in our project root.
Let's see what happens
if we run `vagrant rsync`.
This is an
important take away.
`vagrant rsync` copies files into the vm
from outside, not from the inside out.
And is destructive
by default.
Let's create our
internal file again.
We can leverage
`rsync`'s `-e` option
to set the remote shell command
to `vagrant ssh`.
No hostname is needed
preceeding the colon
since `vagrant ssh` will already access
our vagrant managed machine.
Now the internal file is present in our
external project root and will persist,
even if the machine
is destroyed.
Another cool property
of using `rsync -e`
is that it can copy files
with arbitrary paths in or out.
`vagrant rsync` instead operates
on pre-configured paths--
it takes less typing, but is
less flexible for on-the-fly work.
Let's clean up--
including our external
and internal files.