Here we have
a fresh install of Windows 10.
Let's install
the PSWindowsUpdate module.
With it we can manage updates
from within PowerShell.
PowerShell Gallery is the
central repository for PowerShell code.
This includes both
code projects from Microsoft
and from the greater
PowerShell community.
Research PSWindowsUpdate
and PSGallery as needed
and agree to
the prompt if you so choose.
My current environment is
Windows 10 Home Edition
where the default execution policy
is `Restricted`.
This prevents scripts,
which we now need, from running.
I'm going to set my execution policy
to `RemoteSigned`,
the default for Windows Server.
Check that you also have an execution
policy which allows scripts to run--
preferably the least permissive policy
suitable for your environment.
You can follow the link in the prompt for
more information on execution policies.
Now, we can import the module.
Let's ensure that
our environment is up-to-date.
It is.
If updates are needed, they can
be installed with a few extra flags.
Be sure to only use the `-AutoReboot` flag
if now is a suitable time for a reboot.
And we're done.