We're back on our Ubuntu 22.04
baremetal environment.
Let's make sure
it's up-to-date.
It is.
And this includes the vagrant and VirtualBox
packages we previously installed--
we simply used the native distro packages
included with Ubuntu 22.04.
This is the installation pattern
I would commonly use
and it's enough
for most use cases.
If we just want to ensure
that our environment
has the latest security patches,
we're already done.
We're relying on the Ubuntu project
for a whole operating-systems-worth
of security updates--
what's a few more packages?
That said, there may be times
when it becomes worthwhile
to single out vagrant and install
the newest available version--
say, when you need a specific fix
or feature found in newer vagrant builds.
Let's look at the upgrade process now
using the official vagrant
installation documentation
for Ubuntu as guidance.
Our goal here
is to upgrade vagrant
to the latest HashiCorp provided `.deb`
suitable for Ubuntu 22.04.
vagrant itself is created
and maintained by HashiCorp.
Trusting HashiCorp packages
when already using vagrant seems sensible.
Let's download the `.gpg` key
found on this page.
However, let's write it
to a file in our home directory for now--
we want a bit more verification
before writing it to a restricted path.
Over on the security page
included in HashiCorp's trust center,
we can find the fingerprint
for the `.gpg` key
used for signing linux packages,
including `.deb`s.
For basic validation of an asset securely
downloaded from a trusted domain--
such as this--I'm comfortable
with a simple visual comparison.
I generally compare
the first and last 4-6 characters,
then check one or two random spots
in the middle.
Compare the fingerprints programmatically
as you see fit.
This download
looks good to me.
And now I'll move it
into place.
Next, we need to add the HashiCorp
package repository to our sources lists.
To do so, I'm going copy and paste
the command from the install doc verbatim.
It's worth noting that this one-liner
contains a command substitution.
Be sure you understand each component
of a command before running it.
With the HashiCorp
package source configured,
we again need to update
our indexes of available packages.
Now vagrant should have
an upgrade candidate--let's install it.
To keep things tidy, let's clean up
the stale dependencies
which were pulled in
with our previous vagrant installation.
Time for basic validation.
The upgrade looks good--
at least on the surface.
However, there is a problem
caused by this upgrade
and listing our plugins
will expose it.
In this case, reinstalling our plugins
to pull in
suitable versions of dependencies
is the correct course of action.
Now listing, and more importantly using,
our plugins will work as expected.
And we're done.