Even a cursory look at the vagrant
documentation has a good chance of
uncovering vagrant cloud: the main, public
and searchable, index of vagrant boxes.
We're already aware of the centos/7 box--
let's search for `rockylinux`.
As mentioned previously,
vagrant supports a number of providers.
To use a listed box
it must be available on your provider.
We can see a provider filter menu
just below the search bar.
And provider badges
in the second column of each listing.
These tools will help keep us informed
as we discover boxes.
Let's drill into the first entry,
`rockylinux/8`.
Right away, we're presented
with a simple Vagrantfile.
Switching to the "New" tab, we can see
the same info in `vagrant init` form.
Both of these were covered previously
and should look mostly familiar.
Another thing on this page worth noting
is that this box
is externally hosted by dl.rockylinux.org.
This box is created and maintained
by the rocky linux project--
the same group already relied upon
by using the rocky linux distro.
Trusting distro boxes when already
using distro packages sounds reasonable.
It's also worth mentioning, however, that
there are officially endorsed box sets--
specifically, those found
in the hashicorp or bento namespaces.
vagrant itself is created
and maintained by HashiCorp.
Trusting HashiCorp boxes when already
using vagrant seems sensible.
The bento project is both
part of the well-known
chef automation software testing kit
and officially endosed by HashiCorp.
It contains high-quality,
open-source code
to produce many boxes
across several providers.
Back at our search results, we can see
`bento/rockylinux-8` as the third listing.
This box would
be another sound choice.
Now, we know three easy ways to find
credible boxes: seek out distro boxes,
boxes in the hashicorp namespace,
or boxes in the bento namespace.
vagrant cloud can also be searched
via command line
by using `vagrant cloud search`.
We can see that this information
is very nearly the same
as what's found
in the web portal.
It's even paginated
in a similar way.
Feel free to dig in more now with `vagrant
cloud search --help` if interested.
Searching for boxes via the web portal
has already become a habit for me,
so I'll end here.