Last time, we looked at
using VirtualBox Manager
to access the console
of a vagrant managed machine.
If instead you need frequent access
to the console or GUI, it can be helpful
to instantiate a console window
whenever the machine is brought up.
Let's open our Vagrantfile and set `gui`
to `true` for our VirtualBox provider.
Now whenever we bring our machine up,
a console window is simultaneously created.
Our machine is now booted, but vagrant
is still configuring the environment--
let's let it finish.
`vagrant up` is nearly done.
And let's login.
Time to clean up.
The console window is automatically
closed out during destruction.
I'm going to remove `gui = true`
to reduce graphical clutter,
but feel free to skip or delay
this step as you see fit.