VirtualBox guest additions provide
some decidedly advantageous features.
Among these is
VirtualBox synced folders--
a clear step up from rsync synced folders
for many vagrant use cases.
Let's install the
vagrant-vbguest plugin
which will automate installation
of VirtualBox guest additions.
Conveniently, the needed steps are added
to the `vagrant up` process.
In this case, I'm going to configure
the plugin to upgrade the kernel as needed.
Let's bring
our machine up.
So, why did we need
to allow kernel upgrade?
Installation of
VirtualBox guest additions
includes the building
of a handful of kernel modules.
One of these kmods facilitates
VirtualBox shared folders:
the underlying mechanism
upon which
vagrant's VirtualBox synced folders
are built.
Since we want to explore
VirtualBox synced folders,
we'll need these kmods
to build successfully.
The `centos/7` box I'm using,
version `2004.01`,
contains a
CentOS 7.8 environment.
However, the contained yum repo config
currently points to CentOS 7.9 packages--
7.8 has been archived.
We need version matched
installations
of the kernel and kernel-devel rpms
in order to build our kmods.
A CentOS 7.8 kernel and
7.9 kernel-devel won't do.
We either need to retrieve
kernel-devel from the 7.8 archives,
or upgrade the kernel
to the CentOS 7.9 version.
In this case, the former
gives no advantage,
and the latter is easier to accomplish--
hence, `allow_kernel_upgrade: true`.
Guest additions
are now installed.
Login and we can see
the VirtualBox kmods are loaded.
Let's clean up.