Adding a Vagrantfile, some provisioners,
and few scripts to a project
can dramatically improve
the development workflow.
Formalizing the environment in which
development builds and tests take place
provides much needed consistency--
and vagrant makes doing so easy.
With the vagrant basics
we just walked through,
you should be ready to begin
using vagrant in your own projects.
As you might expect, vagrant has
many features we didn't cover here.
However, the topics covered
should provide
a good foundational understanding
upon which you can build.
Also, don't be afraid
to use vagrant
to simplify the creation, use,
and clean up of ad hoc environments.
Inside a vagrant managed machine,
you can calmly run
that risky command
that may damage the environment.
More importantly, you get to examine
the results and learn something.
Then, you can blow that vm away
and create a fresh one
in its place
in almost no time.
Let me know in the comments
if this info and format was helpful to you.
Like and subscribe
as you see fit.
See ya next time.