Last time, we setup
the vagrant-vbguest plugin
to automate installation
of VirtualBox guest additions.
Now, we're ready to
add a VirtualBox synced folder.
Let's open our Vagrantfile
and add one.
We'll use the same paths
as the rsync synced folder
configured in the box Vagrantfile,
which we saw previously.
We'll set the type
to `virtualbox` here though.
This is a safe pattern and will simply
override the existing rsync synced folder.
Let's create
an external file.
And bring up
our machine.
We can see that
the file exists in /vagrant.
Let's modify it
from outside.
This time the modification is present
inside the vm without any extra steps.
Let's make
an internal file.
This file is present on the outside
without any extra steps.
VirtualBox synced folders require
a bit more setup, but are extremely useful.
Let's clean up.