Here we have macOS 12.6.3 with the
command line developer tools installed.
First, we want to ensure
that our environment is up-to-date.
The basic environment is.
Let's install Homebrew, which is
quite accurately described as
"The Missing
Package Manager for macOS."
The simple installation instructions
over at https://brew.sh
suggest running bash on the output
of a curl to a well-known github domain.
Even though
I have reasonable confidence
that the code
and platforms involved are legitimate,
I won't use this.
First, the download
isn't validated.
Second, there isn't a reliable
way to audit what actually ran.
Instead, I'll clone
the Homebrew install project--
the git checkout process will both
ensure the integrity of install.sh
and place it on-disk,
permitting future examination if desired.
And now I'll run it.
Homebrew makes it easy to install
many tools not included with macOS.
A thriving community
which maintains
thousands of package definitions
covers most common needs.
Package definitions come in two forms,
providing quite a bit of flexibility.
A formula builds and
installs an upstream source project.
A cask installs a project's
pre-built application binaries.
Nowadays, both types are
accessible using `brew install`.
Homebrew simply makes
life on macOS easier
and is well worth the install.
Let's check our installation.
And looks good.