With our synced folder setup, we can easily
pass files into and out of our machine.
Scripts and code can be passed in; build
results and artifacts can be passed out.
Let's look at
a shell script example
which demonstrates an awesome pattern
to use with vagrant.
My projects commonly include `build.sh`:
a shell script which is run
inside a vagrant managed machine
to build the project.
Sometimes my projects have `test.sh`
to run tests
or `prep.sh`
to prepare packed source code.
Composing the specific commands needed
for common project actions
into familiarly named scripts
can save a lot of mental bandwidth
when jumping between projects.
`build.sh` is different
than a provisioner.
Provisioners usually run once
and help setup the environment.
`build.sh` may be called once,
many times, or not at all.
It depends on you're
current use-case.
Let's create
a simple `build.sh`.
Since we're using a VirtualBox synced
folder, marking the script as executable
will affect both our internal
and external environments.
Usually, a build script intended for
a vagrant environment
shouldn't be run
in a baremetal environment.
Therefore, I like to
safeguard against such a case.
My favorite way is to have the script
simply bail out, first thing,
if /vagrant/Vagrantfile
doesn't exist.
This allows
the synced `build.sh`
to be used directly
in our vagrant managed machine.
Another option is to copy `build.sh`
to a non-synced internal path,
then mark it executable.
One drawback of this second approach
is that if you make edits
to the build script,
you have to copy and mark it again.
Let's use the Vagrantfile
safeguard here.
Peculiarly, our demo project has no
formal essence--there's nothing to build,
so we'll use sleep
to simulate the task.
Let's save that.
And set `build.sh`
executable now.
Bring up
our machine.
And run `build.sh`.
There it goes.
Let's clean up.