Here we have an Ubuntu 22.04
baremetal environment
with an outdated
`centos/7` vagrant box.
Let's upgrade it.
Time to verify.
We can see that the new version
is present, as was desired.
However, it may be surprising to find--
on first encounter--
that the old version
is still here too.
vagrant supports multiple versions
of the same box at the same time.
They can be installed
and used side-by-side.
By default new machines will use
the latest installed version of a box.
However, by adding version constraints
in Vagrantfile
new machines can be configured
to use an older version.
In most cases
older versions aren't needed
and removing them frees up
precious storage resources.
A simple `vagrant box prune`
will clean things up nicely.
Verify again and we can see
that the old box is now gone.