When installed, the vagrant-vbguest
plugin will attempt
to install VirtualBox guest additions into
any environment in which they are absent.
While this is generally useful,
there are times when you simply don't need,
or even actively don't want,
guest additions.
Skipping guest additions can save you
a lot of time for certain use cases
and can bypass a bad exit
from `vagrant up` in others.
It's good to know how to disable
this feature when needed.
Let's edit
our Vagrantfile.
We'll comment out our VirtualBox synced
folder and allow kernel upgrade lines.
And finally, set
`vbguest.auto_update` to `false`.
Let's bring
our machine up.
Login and we can see
no VirtualBox kmods are loaded.
Time to clean up.