As we've seen, vagrant lets us create
and manage virtual machine environments
using a single,
simplified workflow.
Last time, we explored codifying common
project actions into well-named scripts.
Let's look at another great way
we can leverage shell scripts
to add convenience
and free-up head space.
Years ago, I was introduced to a pattern
in which you formalize
the most common workflow
for a project as a single command.
Since then,
nearly all of my projects
have included this pattern
in some form or another.
I needed a name for this pattern
and a web search delivered.
In his blog, Wojciech Koszek calls this
idea the "Single Command Principle"--
as serviceable a name
as I've ever heard.
While his post focuses on deployment,
this concept works
just as well
for development workflows.
My go to implementation
for this pattern is `runner.sh`:
a shell script entry point run
on our baremetal environment
to create, make use of, and clean up
a vagrant managed machine.
`runner.sh` wraps and runs every command
needed for our most common workflow--
this could include building, testing,
deploying, and more.
Let's put together
a simple `runner.sh`.
This `runner.sh` can be prepended
with `RUNNER_VAGRANT_DESTROY=false`
to skip destruction
on a given run.
Doing so can be a big time saver by
skipping subsequent environment creations--
especially when changing
or troubleshooting workflows.
I include this
even in the simplest `runner.sh`.
Let's make it
executable.
And run it.
We can see that `runner.sh` created our
machine, ran the build, and cleaned up.
So cool.
To skip destruction,
we'd invoke `runner.sh` like this.
Feel free to explore this more
as you see fit.