Another interesting GUI tool,
especially when using vagrant frequently,
is Vagrant Manager.
Per the project README, "Vagrant Manager
is an OS X status bar menu app that lets
you manage all of your vagrant machines
from one central location."
We can see
at the very top of `README.md`
that there's also
a Vagrant Manager for Windows.
However, unfortunately, Vagrant Manager
isn't available on Linux distros,
like Ubuntu,
at present.
We're back on our macOS 12.6.3
baremetal environment
with Homebrew, VirtualBox,
and vagrant installed.
Vagrant Manager requires the `VBoxManage`
and `vagrant` commands to be in your `$PATH`--
we just verified that this need is met
with our version checks.
Next, we want to ensure
that our environment is up-to-date.
The basic environment is.
Let's check Homebrew.
brew managed installs, including vagrant
and VirtualBox, are up-to-date too.
Let's install Vagrant Manager.
Time to validate our install.
Open Launchpad and select
Vagrant Manager.
Right away, we're met with one flavor
of macOS Gatekeeper prompt.
Per the Gatekeeper documentation,
"When a user downloads and opens an app,
a plug-in, or an installer package
from outside the App Store,
Gatekeeper verifies that the software
is from an identified developer,
is notarized by Apple to be free
of known malicious content,
and hasn’t been altered."
That all sounds great.
However, the Apple Developer Program
membership
required for their services
isn't free.
And, like many open source projects,
Vagrant Manager doesn't meet these standards.
Thankfully, `brew install` will have
already programmatically validated
our Vagrant Manager download using
the SHA-256 included in the cask.
Research Vagrant Manager and Homebrew as
needed and move forward if you so choose.
To move forward, select "Show in Finder",
right click the Vagrant Manager icon,
select "Open" from the menu, and click
"Open" again on the Gatekeeper prompt.
Doing so will automatically add a security
settings exception for Vagrant Manager.
Next time we open it,
we won't have to repeat this process.
Vagrant Manager itself is now prompting
about automatic updates.
I'm going to decline for now,
but feel free to accept as you see fit.
To access Vagrant Manager
now that it's running,
click the newly introduced
"V" icon
in the upper right section
of the macOS status bar.
Our install looks good.