Let's bring up
our machine.
One of vagrant's
strongest features
is that it provides a clean,
well-known starting environment.
As we've seen, provisioners can be used
to enhance these initial environments
by formalizing customizations.
However, some environments are
complex to setup from scratch;
some changes require many
incremental builds or tests.
We want vagrant to assist our work--
not make it slow or tedious.
Therefore, there are times
when it becomes advantageous
to manually run
or rerun provisioners.
`vagrant provision`
meets our needs here.
We can see that our provisioner just ran
and asked yum to install git once again.
It's already installed,
so yum has nothing to do.
`vagrant provision` can be a real time-saver
when developing provisioners themselves--
especially substantial ones which usually
require many incremental tests.
Structuring provisioners
such that they reset
each key part of a complex environment,
to a known state,
can avoid the need
to repeat slow initial setups.
A declarative configuration tool
like puppet
might have an advantage
over shell provisioners here.
Another option is to provide
the formalization in another layer.
I constantly use mock to build rpms
from inside a vagrant environment.
I've also run docker inside
a vagrant managed machine
to provide structure
to certain tasks.
An optimal solution all depends
on the particulars of the use-case.
Let's clean up.