So far, we've configured vagrant by adding
settings to our project Vagrantfile.
Another option is to apply config
to a user-level Vagrantfile
found in your vagrant home--
by default `~/.vagrant.d/`.
Let's start by deleting the `auto_update`
line from our project Vagrantfile.
As we saw previously, if we
run `vagrant up` with this config,
the vagrant-vbguest plugin
will attempt to install guest additions.
Let's change the plugin's
default behavior for our user
to skip
guest additions installation.
To do this, we simply
create a Vagrantfile in our vagrant home,
add the basic config structure,
and set `vbguest.auto_update` to `false`--
essentially, the same thing
as we did in our project Vagrantfile.
Let's bring
our machine up.
Login and again we can see
no VirtualBox kmods are loaded.
Time to clean up.