We're back in our demo directory
with our centos/7 Vagrantfile.
The Vagrantfile produced by `vagrant init`
comes with a lot of comments.
I personally don't like
to keep these around
and prefer to avoid adding
clutter of this sort to source control.
I'm going to remove the comments,
but feel free to skip or delay this step
to take a peek at them.
Let's take a look
at our remaining Vagrantfile.
It's pretty simple ruby code
at the moment--
little more than
setting the box to `centos/7`.
And we supplied that as an
argument to `vagrant init` last time.
Let's make some edits.
I'm going to install vim to do so,
but feel free to use any editor you like.
Let's add some additional cpu
and memory resources.
And save that.
Start our machine.
Login.
We can see our cpu count
matches what we set.
As does our memory--
more or less.
We can get a more accurate value
with a less common command.
The total online memory exactly matches
the value we set in Vagrantfile.
Time to clean up.