Here we have Windows 10
with the PSWindowsUpdate
PowerShell module installed.
Our first step is to ensure
that the environment is up-to-date.
The basic environment is.
If updates are needed, they can
be installed with a few extra flags.
Be sure to only use the `-AutoReboot` flag
if now is a suitable time for a reboot.
Now, let's install winget
and a few dependencies.
Without a package manager,
we'll have to install them manually.
The process for each package
will look quite similar--
we'll download one or more assets,
extract as needed,
validate what we're about to install,
and then install it.
First up is
the Windows UI Library, UI Xaml.
Let's download the nuget
linked in the project's README.
We don't have .NET installed, but--
like many package formats--
a .nupkg is really just an archive.
We'll name our download
with the .zip extension
since some Windows tools
are picky about those.
Extract the .zip
to get at the .appx file.
Let's validate the embedded
digital signature in the .appx.
Looks good.
Let's install that.
Next, we need
the Visual C++ Runtime libraries.
Let's download the .appx linked
in the Visual Studio
troubleshooting documentation.
Validate the digital signature.
Good to go.
And install.
With the dependencies installed,
we can now install
the Windows Package Manager CLI,
also known as winget.
Let's download the .msixbundle
from the project's github releases.
This project also provides
a SHA-256 of the .msixbundle
in the correspondingly named .txt file.
Let's compare the SHA
contained in the .txt file
to our downloaded .msixbundle.
For basic validation of an asset securely
downloaded from a trusted domain--
such as this--I'm comfortable
with a simple visual comparison.
I generally compare
the first and last 4-6 characters,
then check one or two random spots
in the middle.
Compare the hashes programmatically
as you see fit.
This download looks good to me.
Time to install.
Let's check our installation.
Looks good.