Here we have a
fresh install of macOS 12.6.3.
First, we want to ensure
that our environment is up-to-date.
The basic environment is.
Let's install
the command line developer tools.
Click the install button
on the gui prompt to move forward.
Read the license agreement
and click agree if you so choose.
Now the command line developer tools,
part of Apple's Xcode IDE, are installing.
The command line developer tools contain
many useful executables, including git.
In addition to the value
it provides directly,
git is also needed to install Homebrew
and run installs with Homebrew.
git can also
be installed via Homebrew,
but we need git
in order to install Homebrew.
This approach isn't going to work--
at least not at this stage.
Of course, we can always
build git from source.
Doing so requires we
have the needed build toolchain.
An easy way to get that is to install
the command line developer tools.
Notice a pattern here--
when using macOS,
you'll likely want to install
the command line developer tools.
Let's validate our install.
And more importantly, let's validate
one of the installed executables.
Looks good.