Here we have Windows 10 with the
PSWindowsUpdate PowerShell module
and winget installed.
First, we want to ensure
that our environment is up-to-date.
The basic environment is.
If updates are needed, they can
be installed with a few extra flags.
Be sure to only use the `-AutoReboot` flag
if now is a suitable time for a reboot.
Let's check winget.
If you have a fresh install
of winget, as I do,
you should see an agreement prompt
for the msstore source.
Follow the link to read the terms
and agree if you so choose.
winget managed installs
are up-to-date too.
If winget upgrades are needed,
they can be install with the `--all` flag.
Our goal here is to
install vagrant and VirtualBox.
To do so, we first need to install
Microsoft Visual C++ Redistributable--
a dependency of VirtualBox.
Now, we can install VirtualBox.
Let's do some basic validation.
VirtualBox looks good.
Next, let's install vagrant.
VirtualBox is a well-known,
cross-platform hypervisor
and provides a virtualization platform
upon which vagrant can run machines.
vagrant calls the virtualization platforms
it can use providers.
VirtualBox happens to be
vagrant's default provider
making it arguably
the easiest way to get started.
vagrant supports
several other providers,
either natively
or through installable plugins.
Time for some more
basic validation.
vagrant looks good too.