In the real world, you'll probably have to
set a project aside from time-to-time.
Sometimes this means devoting your cpu and
memory resources to another cause.
The good news is that typical commands
like `shutdown`, `halt`, and `poweroff`
work as expected when run inside
a vagrant managed machine.
When you want the machine back up,
you simply run `vagrant up` again.
Other times you may want to shutdown
or reboot a machine you can't access,
rather than destroy it.
If you're troubleshooting a kernel panic,
developing a config for kdump,
testing a newly manipulated initrd,
or similar
`vagrant halt` will
undoubtedly come in handy.
These options point out
another skill we need:
the ability to find
the current state of a machine.
We can use `vagrant status`
to see this.
Right now,
the state is "not created",
which makes sense since the last thing
we did was `vagrant destroy`.
Let's bring up our machine.
Now, status shows
that it's "running".
Let's log in briefly
and create a new file.
Then halt the machine.
Another status check shows that
it's in the "poweroff" state.
Let's bring our vm back up.
We can see
that our file persisted.
This is a key difference
between `destroy` and `halt`.
`destroy` doesn't persist storage
that is exclusive to the vm.
`halt` doesn't free storage resources
consumed by the vm.
Both are useful
for different cases.
Let's clean up.
A final `vagrant status` and we see that
our state has returned to "not created".