Here we have new installs
of vagrant and VirtualBox.
Let's go through the same steps
we just saw on Ubuntu--
this time using a Windows 10
baremetal environment.
By doing so, we'll get to see just
how similar the commands and outputs look,
even when run on a dissimilar
baremetal environment.
To start using vagrant,
we need a Vagrantfile.
A Vagrantfile typically lives
in a project, often in the project root.
Let's create a directory called demo
to serve as our new project root.
Next, we need
a machine definition.
`vagrant init` makes creating
a basic definition simple.
My baremental environment is Windows,
so let's make our vm environment CentOS 7.
The format change
of the prompt
will make it clear in which environment
each command is run.
We can see a Vagrantfile
is now present.
Let's spin up our machine.
One helpful feature
of `vagrant up` is that
it automatically downloads
the configured box if absent.
Another option is to use `vagrant box`
which let's you directly manage boxes.
`vagrant box` includes subcommands
such as `add`, `update`, and `remove`.
`vagrant box add` could have been
used to download the centos/7 box
ahead of `vagrant up`.
In this case, we're using
the box right away,
so there's no advantage
to pre-fetching.
However, it's an interesting option
to keep in mind.
Now that our machine is running,
we can access it with `vagrant ssh`.
A quick look in /etc/
and we can confirm
that this is indeed
a CentOS 7 environment.
Feel free to poke around
in this environment more now.
When ready to leave,
simply logout.
I tend to use control-d
to do so.
Finally, we use `vagrant destroy`
to clean up.
That vm is now gone and the cpu,
memory, and storage resources
it was consuming
have been freed.
So cool.