As we've seen, `vagrant up` can create
a new machine from a boxed environment
in about a minute--
which is already amazing.
However, many projects have
additional environmental requirements.
We want to avoid running
a bunch of setup commands
every time we create
a new environment.
Likewise, building, managing,
and maintaining one or more custom boxes
for each project, or even project class,
would quickly become burdensome.
Thankfully, vagrant supports
shell scripts, puppet manifests,
ansible playbooks,
and more as provisioners.
Provisioners let you customize
the environment to meet the needs
of your project--install dependencies,
modify configuration,
start a service or two,
whatever you need.
The best part is that provisioners run
"on the first `vagrant up`
that creates the environment"--
no additional commands needed.
Leveraging provisioners to customize
our environments is highly useful,
so let's dig in
with a shell script example.
When provisioning requirements
for a project are simple,
it's clean and easy to satisfy them all
in a single script named `provisioner.sh`.
As provisioning requirements increase in
complexity, `provisioner.sh` can be split
into smaller scripts and organized in
a provisioners directory or tree.
One common need
for my projects is git.
Perhaps to clone a requirement, generate
a version string using `git describe`,
or even automatically import
and commit upstream code--
particularly that found
in source rpms.
Let's make a simple script
which installs git.
Add it to our machine definition
as a shell provisioner.
And bring up
our machine.
Let's validate
our git installation.
This time we'll pass our command
into the vm using `vagrant ssh -c`.
Let's clean up.
We'll run `vagrant destroy -f`
to force destruction
without being prompted
for confirmation.