Here we have macOS 12.6.3
with Homebrew installed.
First, we want to ensure
that our environment is up-to-date.
The basic environment is.
Let's check Homebrew.
brew managed installs
are up-to-date too.
Let's install vagrant
and VirtualBox.
VirtualBox is a well-known,
cross-platform hypervisor
and provides a virtualization platform
upon which vagrant can run machines.
vagrant calls the virtualization platforms
it can use providers.
VirtualBox happens to be
vagrant's default provider
making it arguably
the easiest way to get started.
vagrant supports
several other providers,
either natively
or through installable plugins.
Time for basic validation.
And the install looks good.