Let's bring up
our machine.
Another highly desirable skill
is to be able
to access the console
of vagrant managed machines.
This is especially useful
when doing low-level work--
say, troubleshooting boot issues
or looking into a softlockup.
Alternatively, if your
vagrant managed machine is running a GUI,
you can access it
using these same methods.
I've used the GUI
of a vagrant managed machine
to access legacy ipmi web portals
requiring ancient java components.
GUI use cases for vagrant
definitely exist.
Similarly to shutdown commands,
the native method for console access
provided by your hypervisor
should still work.
In the case of VirtualBox,
we can simply open the VirtualBox Manager,
select the appropriate machine, and select
show to bring up the console or GUI.
This method is especially useful
for machines that are already running.
Let's clean up.