Hey guys. Werekraken here.
Welcome to the channel.
Today we'll be talking about vagrant--
an awesome tool
which makes the creation, use,
and clean up of development environments,
generally in the form of virtual machines,
simple and repeatable.
But first,
ladies, gentlemen:
I don't care if you prefer linux or unix,
like and subscribe.
And don't forget
to comment.
So, here we are
for my first video series.
I wanted to kick things off
with vagrant fundamentals
since I use this tool nearly every day
in my work as a computing professional.
One of vagrant's strongest features
is that it provides
a clean, well-known starting environment
that others can reproduce.
In this series, we'll explore
the foundational knowledge
to use vagrant
in this way.
The content is
primarily targeted
at established or aspiring
computing professionals and hobbyists.
I assume the viewer has
basic command line proficiency
and won't be stopping
to describe every command.
Visit the project website,
vagrantup.com,
and nearly the first thing you'll see
is "Development environments simplified."--
the vagrant project
really delivers on this claim.
vagrant makes creating a virtual machine
to research a question, work out a procedure,
or develop code against
more accessible than ever before.
The machines are defined in a Vagrantfile:
plain-text ruby code
suitable to be added
to source control management.
Adding a Vagrantfile to your project
let's you formalize a development, build,
or test environment that can be
passed along, right with the code.
We'll look at installation of vagrant
on several baremetal environments.
Feel free to watch just the videos
matching your baremetal environment--
the install videos are structured to include
the same general information about vagrant,
so you won't miss
any fundamentals by doing so.
If you're unsure where you might use vagrant,
watch the installation on Ubuntu.
This should provide a reasonable
general understanding of the process,
in addition to covering
this specific environment.
And it's both the shortest
installation procedure
and the least encumbered
with extra steps.
If you have a different starting environment,
head over to the vagrantup downloads page
and select the appropriate tab to get
specific guidance on your environment.
See you in
the next video.